Everyone always asks me what is the
difference between greenfield and
brownfield? Will your skills work on
brownfield or will they only work on
greenfield? And let me tell you
something. Greenfield and brownfield are
basically the same thing. Whatever
you're building, you are building for
the real world. And in the real world,
there is really no such thing as a
greenfield. You are always working
around external constraints, working to
integrate with existing software,
working to, you know, solve real-world
problems. And the only difference
between a greenfield and brownfield code
base is that you haven't sorted out the
experience of working in that code base
yet. In a brownfield code base, you
already have existing coding
conventions. You have probably an
existing test suite. You have existing
coding standard. Probably, you know,
most of them do. Even if they're not
documented, they are implicit in the
code that's already been written. But in
greenfield, you get to choose all of
that out of the gate. But once you've
made those choices and AI has spat a
bunch of code out into the repo, then,
you know, there's an element of those
choices become harder to change as you
go on. So, how long does your greenfield
code base stay green? Like, not very
long, you know, maybe a couple of days,
maybe a week at most. We are able to
move from fresh code base to legacy code
base at a faster rate than ever before.
So, I really don't think the greenfield
versus brownfield distinction actually
matters that much. And yes, brownfield
code bases can have a lot of code in
them, but you can actually make them
pretty easy to navigate and easy to work
through if you just design your
documentation properly, if you design
your folder structure properly.